And now for something strange and new.
my next guests are part of the upcoming.
highly anticipated Star Trek series.
Strange New Worlds.
which continues the adventures
of Captain Pike. Spock. and Number One.
aboard the U.S.S. Enterprise.
coming soon to CBS
All Access in the U.S.
Now. it is my honor to welcome our cast
and creatives together
for the first time ever
to talk about the series.
We have Anson Mount. Ethan
Peck and Rebecca Romijn
and we also have executive producers.
Akiva Goldsman and Henry Alonso Myers.
as well as co-EPs and writers.
Akela Cooper and Davy Perez.
Let's start in on some questions.
This one is for Akiva and Henry.
When did you decide
that Strange New Worlds
would actually become a reality?
Since I know there was a
huge fan push for the show
to even get made before
it was announced.
I. uh. uh... came into. uh.
Season 1 of Disco
because our partner.
Alex Kurtzman. was away
and asked me if I could come
and sort of hang around
the show a little while.
it was just forming.
And I didn't know what
the show was about.
I'm a huge Star Trek
fan. but all I knew was
what was on the Internet. and
what was on the Internet was.
it was a show about Captain
Pike and Number One.
So I came rushing to the first meeting.
ready to talk about Captain
Pike and Number One.
only to discover that not only
were they not in the show.
but from that moment on.
became my singular cause
of trying to get that era
of Enterprise storytelling
onto the screen.
My favorite thing I've
read about this show
has been that if you
think of "The Cage".
the original pilot as
being the actual pilot.
that this is the longest pilot to
series pickup in the
history of television.
I can't take credit for it.
but I'll say it anyway.
For Akiva and Henry. Akela and Davy.
I know you can't say much yet.
but what can you tell us
about what the show is about?
Well. one of the most
exciting things about
this was coming into the room
and interviewing all the
writers and basically saying.
"Hey. we wanna really do Star Trek.
like we wanna do Star
Trek in the classic mode".
Star Trek in the way that Star
Trek was always. you know.
the stories were always
told. that it's a ship
and it's traveling to
strange new worlds.
and we're gonna tell big ideas.
science fiction adventures.
you know. in an episodic
mode. so we have room
to kind of meet new
aliens. see new ships.
visit new cultures.
And. you know. while
still maintaining...
audiences are sophisticated.
and so. if Kirk falls in love
and the love of his life
dies one week. the next
week. he's gonna still feel it.
And that's the thing that we really
wanted to kind of carry over.
is to bring a modern
character sensibility
to the kind of classic
episodic storytelling.
For Anson. Ethan and
Rebecca. after Season 2
of Discovery. we didn't know
if we'd actually ever see
your characters again.
and for each of you.
can you guys describe the
moment you got that call
that Strange New Worlds was happening?
How and when did you hear about it?
How did you feel?
When we finished Season 2.
Alex had already started
talking to us about
doing some Short Treks
'cause we had built this huge.
very expensive bridge.
I remember
calling Alex because I was
a little concerned about
what are we actually giving them other
than just three scenes?
Is there some way that we
could give this closure?
And he said. "That's a good
point. Let me think about that".
And so. he calls me two days later.
and I remember him sort of
nonchalantly eating an apple
on the phone. and he goes.
"Hey. so I think we got a show".
"A what?"
Only man I know who can go
and sell a show in two days.
But what I found out later.
apparently. that Akiva
had been pitching this for a while.
And I was like. "I'm so glad
you didn't tell me that"
when I was working on Discovery.
'cause I don't think I could
have handled the pressure...
I got a phone call also
from Alex. very nonchalant.
It wasn't eating an apple.
but led in with a bunch of questions.
Like. "How are you doing?"
What've you been up to?
So. uh...
Your show's going...
And I was like.
"Are you serious?"
Asking the most serious
man in the world. right?
And he was like. "Uh-huh".
And I went for a walk. like in shock.
And went to the grocery store.
and like stood in and
stared at cold beverages
for 20 minutes. and I
called Anson and I was like.
"Dude. this is crazy".
And then the three of us got
into a call at some point.
I was gonna say. we've been sitting
on this information for a while.
Like we've been sitting on it
for. I mean over a year. guys?
Is that right?
We didn't get an actual
green light. green light.
- Right.
- It was a long process.
But it felt like there...
It also felt like when we were on set.
something had clicked.
We were really hoping that
this would manifest. and it did.
It just took a while for us to
be able to share the news.
Yeah. there is definitely
a ton of moments on set
where we were all like. "This is great.
We get along wonderfully".
For Akela and Davy.
can you guys talk a little bit about
how you'll be developing
the central trio?
Not just as colleagues. but as
friends as they clearly are.
which is heartwarming.
I think it's just like
building off of the dynamic
that Disco like so wonderfully built.
And then for us. the
fun thing in the room
has been coming up with
cool and unique situations
and scenarios to put them in.
that will bring out certain aspects
of their personalities
that we can play with
and see how they would
bounce off of each other.
complement each but also
contrasts against each other
and just see how
those puzzle pieces fit.
Like that's been the most fun for us.
Yeah. no. echoing all of that
and I'll just add one little thing
that we did have conversations
about Pike and Number One.
sort of being almost like
parental figures to the ship
and in specific. Spock. 'cause
Spock is a younger Spock.
he's not the wise old Spock
from the original series.
This is the young guy who's
just out of Starfleet Academy
and still finding himself
and what kind of Spock
will he become?
And so. you have great
mentor relationships.
mentee relationships. and
often times you can learn
from your own kids just
as much as you teach.
So there's a lot of interesting
relationship dynamics
that's played in there.
Anson. we saw in Discovery
what a born leader Captain Pike is.
but he also know harbors the
knowledge of his tragic future.
Can you kind of talk about this
unique side of the character
and how you'll inform your
performance. if at all?
The most honest thing I can say
is I'm still figuring it out.
and it's gonna... I think
more of that weight
is gonna come down on the
shoulders of the writers. but.
Pike didn't just learn how he dies.
he learns in what circumstances.
So we do know that at some point
he's going to be presented
with a promotion opportunity
to Fleet Captain.
and he has to accept that
in order for the fate
to come into existence.
So what is it that's going to allow him.
both in terms of
circumstance and emotion.
to accept that promotion.
It's a tough question.
but I think we'll
figure it out together.
I know that I'm excited to
watch you figure it out.
so I'm sure all the fans are as well.
Ethan. in the final scene
of Discovery Season 2.
we finally saw the Spock that
fans are pretty familiar with
from the original series.
So are you excited to explore
more of that iconic side
of the character post
the Discovery encounter?
Yeah. I'm very thrilled to...
to find the balance in Spock. right?
He's between two worlds of...
uh. logic and control
and sort of emotional volatility
that we all struggle with.
And so.
it's gonna be an enormous challenge
and there are plenty of scenarios
in which we could
sort of play with that.
and I'm very excited to see
what the writers come up with
and I'm just gonna throw
myself in. I can't wait.
Awesome.
And for Rebecca. of the
three main characters.
Number One is by far the most enigmatic.
So for you. what are you
most interested to learn
about your character moving forward?
Yeah. well. I mean. like "The Cage"
being such an old pilot.
the writers have this
very unique opportunity
where they've had this
character that's existed
since the beginning of the canon;
She's never been written.
I can't wait to find out. you
know. how vast her skillset is.
what are the arrows in her quiver?
My number one question is
what's her backstory.
and I had a delightful meeting
with the writers' room
a couple months ago.
and they floated an idea
for Number One's backstory
that I'm not gonna share right now
'cause it is... it blew my
mind when they said it.
but that's all I can say.
Well. if you're excited.
I know everyone else will be excited.
So man. now I just really
want the show to come out.
For Akiva and for Henry.
how will this show set itself apart
from previous Star Trek series?
Well. I think as Henry said earlier.
we're returning to a more episodic model
so that the storytelling
is more contained
with episodic values.
while the character arcs
are stretched in some
more serialized continuity.
But in addition to that.
I think that what you heard is that
this is a love child. right?
There's this fundamental
opportunity to feel
like you're part of a thing
you've always wanted to be part of.
That we do for a living.
a thing that we would
do for free. right?
I mean. none of us didn't
play Star Trek. right?
And here we are playing Star Trek.
but somebody's giving
us sets and costumes
and. occasionally. even a check.
And so. we are situated
not just in the context
of all our own affection for the object.
we're also situated in the
history of the object. right?
We. unlike the new shows.
Discovery or Picard.
this exists in its own space.
in a space where it is both imagined
generally by those who came before us.
but never has actually been
delved into specifically.
That it's the opportunity of dreams
that a lot of people
have already dreamt.
And so now we're going to find our way
through that and work not to be...
sentimental.
We get to dream other people's
dreams by dreaming our own.
and that's kind of insane.
It's a space that other people
are already holding dear.
that we now have to be the custodian.
I have this reminder every day
'cause I have a 10-year-old
and a 13-year-old.
And I have been... as I've been
watching a lot of old Trek.
I've been introducing them to the show
and much to sort of my... I
guess. not really a surprise
but it's been a real
joy... is that my kids
have become the biggest Trekkies
that you can possibly imagine.
Yeah. this has been the great surprise
and fun of this job is that they...
this is maybe the first
show I've worked on.
where they are really
excited to see the show.
And what's been fun is.
everyone here has told a
story about their childhood
and how Trek came into it.
And here. I feel like we're... as
we create this next chapter.
it's been 20 years since.
Voyager ended. and Voyager
was a kind of an episodic
model. and here we are doing it
for a new generation.
And like I have... it's
nice to have that vision
right in front of you to
see that new generation
excited about it.
Henry and Akiva kind of touched
on this question a little bit before.
but Akela and Davy. I
kind of want you guys
to delve in a little bit more
on how much you guys
will be balancing the
episodic storylines
with the more serialized style
of the newer Star Trek shows
when breaking into Strange New Worlds.
Well. we'll have like
individual. one-off plots.
The character arcs are
what's going to carry us
through in a more
serialized fashion. Though.
I will say there's
probably one plot point
that we will be sprinkling
through the series
until we actually get to the episode.
and that's all I can say about that.
And what's really cool.
And we've all touched on
it. is that we sort of look
at each episode is what
is the thing we're saying?
And what is the audience
gonna experience?
And so. that's the fun of going
back to an episodic style.
It's like. what cool type
of episode will this be?
What kind of a thing will
we walk away from it.
in a close-ended kind of way?
And that's the episode of the week.
But these are the characters
that... Pike and Number One
and Spock. they're the trio
that we're gonna fall in love with
and they're gonna have their
character emotional things.
And we're gonna. they're gonna grow
and devolve and evolve and
come back and enjoy all of that.
For Rebecca. little change of pace here.
Your husband. Jerry.
is also a number one
on Star Trek: Lower Decks.
So how much do you guys
talk about Star Trek.
watch Star Trek together?
I know you said that you
watch it with your kids.
like how is Star Trek in the household?
It is nonstop competition at our house.
We are continually... we can't
stop letting each other know
that we are the best
number... that I am.
that I let him know over and over again
that I am the best number one.
He has brought it to my attention
that number one means
you're second in command.
which I've explained to him.
I am second in command
to our cat. ironically.
whose name is Captain.
He's the only one that
I'm second in command to.
Oh my goodness. this could
be its own miniseries.
honestly. like you guys
are setting up something amazing here.
I am the better number
one. I've let him know.
We'll let you have that
crown today. 100%.
In our house! Because
I don't wanna. listen.
I don't wanna tick
off Jonathan Frakes...
there are other people that I.
this is in our own household. like in...
in the world of number ones.
I don't know.
If I have to call Jonathan
and tell him your crown has
been taken away today. I will.
I will give it to you. it's okay.
You are the superior number one.
You're brave. Thank you.
I do wanna be clear
without violating any
confidentiality agreements.
that I have already begun agitating
for the crossover episode.
- Oh.
- Wait. with Lower Decks or...
So like a live action. a
live action. animated...?
- Roger Rabbit?
- Okay.
I was about to say.
is this some sort of Who
Framed Roger Rabbit?
Like. I'm into it.
I love it.
- Fun.
- Oh man. we're getting
a bunch of exclusives. let's.
that... panel over.
that's the best news.
In space. anything can happen. you guys.
One dimension could be animated
and they find a portal to it.
- We're writing an episode right now.
- We've never seen subspace.
Oh man. I love this.
For Anson and Ethan and Rebecca.
what kind of research did you guys do
to prepare for these roles?
And are you rewatching
more Star Trek now
that Strange New Worlds is happening.
if that's even possible?
I mean. you guys do
watch a lot of Star Trek.
I've just been rewatching
the original series.
I've got. like I said.
I've got it on my DVR.
There are things these days
that wake me up in the wee hours.
maybe other people are going
through that these days.
and watching the original series
at two in the morning
sometimes helps. It's soothing.
It's nice to have around.
I just. you know. I went back and I...
obviously. I rewatched "The Cage"
and "The Menagerie". and
I read what I could find
in canon online. but.
I think most of my preparation
as an actor usually is just
a way to calm my nerves.
I had to come in and discover the Pike
that was in a different part of his life
then he had been in those episodes.
So. luckily I had the
support of great writers
and a team that made
sure that those writers
were present on the set
during their episodes
when they're being shot.
and I depended upon them most of all.
Yeah. I spent a lot of time
with the original series
with Leonard Nimoy and his Spock.
I read I Am Not Spock and I Am Spock
that... he wrote both.
And I read a book called The
Nature of... The Order of Time
by Carlo Rovelli. which is
a theoretical physics book
that I thought really connected to
what they were sort of tapping
into on the Discovery ship.
And yeah. as I go forward.
I'm probably gonna rewatch
the episodes I watched
of the original series.
watch it all over again.
And I'm actually getting
into some older philosophy.
'Cause I realized this is
such a virtuous person.
and so I want to kind of explore
what people have been thinking about
over the millennia
basically. 'cause I feel
like that's what Spock would do.
So I picked up some Aristotle
and some Kant and Confucius
and we'll start there
and see how it goes.
I love it. some deep Method work there.
For Akiva and Henry. as
we move closer and closer
to the original series era.
will we start to see
more of that aesthetic
reflected in Strange New Worlds?
One of the great joys
of this job has been...
We meet weekly with our
incredibly talented production
and design team. and we look
over these incredible sets.
For us. I think the fun of
it has been figuring out
how to keep continuity with the past.
how to keep some of the
amazing design elements
from the '60s that were
incorporated in the first one
and update it for a modern audience.
The Enterprise is sexy
is all I got to say.
it's a sexy. sexy ship.
I think everybody loves their own ship.
but I gotta agree with you.
it is. it is a pretty sexy ship.
For the creative team. Akiva.
Henry. Akela and Davy.
as the title suggests. this show
will clearly be introducing
new planets and alien species.
But given the time period
the show is set in.
there seems to be plenty of
opportunities for references
to legacy material as well.
Obviously. without any spoilers.
is there something you guys are
talking about in the writers' room
you can give us a little taste of?
The storytelling itself is using sci-fi
to say something about
the world around us
and that in and of
itself is. like. a way
to touch upon the legacy.
We're obviously gonna be. like. mining
as much as we can of
the original series.
and if we can reach
into Next Gen some way.
but a lot of us...
and the conversations we're having...
are like. those original series episodes
and that TNG era and Deep Space Nine.
were using episodic television
to say something really introspective
or really important about
the world around us
and about ourselves as human species
and what we could be in the future.
and that kind of legacy storytelling
is how we're sort of gonna
really look at each episode
as we move forward.
I think they wanted spoilers.
I know. I wanna say it. but I can't.
It's understandable.
And finally. since we're
all here for Star Trek Day.
what does it mean to
all of you to be a part
of this legacy as Star Trek.
since you guys aren't just fans.
but now you're in it. like you said.
you get paid to play Star Trek.
Star Trek is important to
us for the same reason
that we'd like to think it's important.
Star Trek is not value neutral.
Star Trek is the future we want.
It is a galaxy that is
multicultural. multiethnic.
multigendered; It is a galaxy
where empathy prevails.
It is a galaxy where goodness resonates
and kindness and compassion
and the ability to build bridges.
and those are the
grammar of exploration.
And Star Trek has always been of value
because it's a carnival
mirror on our time.
It lets us look at the world around us.
by looking at an imagined
world. and we need that.
We need hope. we need those
values. we need optimism.
certainly as sorely as
any time before us.
Maybe we're tied for when
the original series came out.
So. on Star Trek Day. we
hope to make Star Trek
so that every day has the
values that Star Trek prefers.
And we mean it.
Building on what Akiva just said.
It's. I mean. it's never felt
like a more important time
to be telling stories based
on these themes of optimism
and a bright future. and I can't wait
to start telling those stories
because I think we've all
been having a hard time.
And actually. I just started...
the world has become
overwhelming lately.
And I mean. I just broke
down in tears the other day
about the post office.
I mean. it's just everything.
and I know everyone's going through it.
And I actually just
started feeling envious
of the writers' room
that they get to channel these
themes right now of optimism.
And the thing is. what
we... what these stories
that we're telling...
they are imaginary.
we're making it up. but
those themes are not.
Those themes of
optimism and bright future
need to be inspired and manifested
and the writers get to
be living that right now.
and I can't wait to start
telling those stories.
It's just. it's an honor to
be a part of it. obviously.
it's such an incredible
family to be a part of.
but especially now I wanna
start telling these stories.
So thank you. writers.
I'm jealous that
you're already living it.
Come on over. Come on in.
I think one possible
definition of the human being
is the cross section of
curiosity and creativity.
as manifested by that need
we have to walk past...
walk away from the circle of firelight
and into the darkness
to see what's out there.
is an incredibly beautiful
thing about our species.
And I think that.
Star Trek fully realizes that.
When you think about
our current endeavors.
we're pouring billions
of dollars and man hours
and ingenuity into
getting people to Mars.
and pretty much everybody is going.
"Yeah. that makes sense".
But when you do step back
and think about it. it's crazy.
but there's something in
us that needs to do that.
to expand. and Star
Trek. it just reflects
what's best about us in that sense.
Yeah. I believe that Star Trek
has never been afraid to
shine light where it is dark.
and I'm incredibly proud to
be one of those torchbearers.
And I hope that it will inspire.
not just those that see
it. but in the future.
people that see it. It's
inspired me. certainly.
and makes me wanna be a better person.
I think it's all about
graduating ourselves
to sort of greater unity and
acceptance and curiosity.
Reflecting on what Star Trek means to me
as a black woman.
watching Uhura and Sisko.
it was black people
made it to the future.
And in a lot of science fiction.
you don't actually see
people of color in the future.
especially in the '70s and '80s.
And so. for me. that
was a symbol of like.
you are here. like. you made it.
And as Akiva pointed out.
like when the original series came out.
it was a time of turmoil and upheaval.
And we're in that now.
but in the history of Star Trek.
they also went through a
lot of turmoil and upheaval
and they made it through.
And I think that's like the
best message for Star Trek.
especially now. is that
there is a way through.
and there is hope. and
there is a positive future
and we will all get there.
And being a writer on the
show. it's also. it's like.
I saw "you are here"
in the black characters
in the future. and now
I'm in the writers' room.
and I am here. And it hits me sometimes
that like. I grew up watching this
with my parents my whole life.
and now I'm writing on
a show that they love.
and that I love. and I am
here. and it's wonderful.
Yeah. I'm having a moment too.
I'm trying not to. like. choke up
because... Why did I say that?
Now I'm gonna choke up!
Oh no...
My. my... You know. I'm a son
of an immigrant. and my father.
he came to this country. and
he would look to the stars.
like he wanted to go to space
and he didn't make it to space.
but Star Trek was close
enough for him. you know?
And so. he put a love
of that exploration
and that curiosity inside of me.
And now. here I am.
I get to go to space.
I get to go to this place in the future
full of what we could become
and what is the best of us.
So yeah. it means a lot.
It's a very personal and a
fantastic and overwhelming thing.
and I'm not going to choke up!
You keep saying it...
I know. I know.
Ah shoot. sorry.
Anyway. Star Trek means
a lot to me and my family
and Star Trek Day is just.
it's a great way to
celebrate all of that.
I think one of the greatest
things about Star Trek
is that it is an ensemble.
It is made up of people
from all different races
and planets and creeds.
And I think that the... doing
the show is the same thing.
and I'm incredibly grateful
to. on Star Trek Day.
to be here working with this team
and all of their
incredible personal stories
that they have brought
and gifted to the show.
So. I wanna end by saying.
just to say thank you to everyone.
Now that we're all
emotional and teary-eyed
and really feeling connected.
I just wanna thank you guys so much
for joining me for this chat.
This was beautiful and inspirational.
And just seeing your love
and passion for Star Trek.
I know in my heart and
know that all the fans
in their hearts that Strange New Worlds
is going to be just. just mind-blowing.
Thanks so much for
joining me for this chat.
I cannot wait to see what's
coming on Strange New Worlds.
Again. for those watching at home.
we'll be coming soon to CBS All
Access in the United States.
And again. today on Star Trek Day.
you too can pitch in and support
our Star Trek United Campaign.
For every person that tweets the hashtag
#StarTrekUnitedGives. CBS
All Access will donate $1
to organizations who
do the real world work
of championing equality. social justice.
and the pursuit of
scientific advancements.
So thank you guys so much.
and take care everybody.
Get those tissues.
- Bye. happy Star Trek Day!
- Happy Star Trek Day!
Happy Star Trek Day!
Live long and prosper.
Sync & corrections by Costa Dax
www.addic7ed.com